# **Nick Joshua Montemayor**

 $+639949320841 \cdot nickjoshuamontemayor 0121@gmail.com \cdot www.linkedin.com/in/nickjmont Angeles City, Pampanga$ 

Highly skilled IT specialist who finished Magna Cum Laude from STI College-Angeles with a Bachelor of Science in Information Technology. Extensive knowledge of programming (C#, Python, JavaScript), database management (MS SQL, MongoDB), and network configuration. Exhibits great troubleshooting skills and significant experience in computer hardware and maintenance. Known for problem-solving and critical thinking abilities, as well as a proactive and adaptable attitude to overcoming complicated technical challenges.

# **SKILLS**

- Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, Kali), Windows
- Networking: TCP/IP, OSI Model, VPN, Subnetting
- Programming Languages: Java, C#, Python, JavaScript, PHP
- Databases: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite
- **Tools**: Unity, Android Studio, Visual Studio, MS SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), Oracle Virtual Box
- Soft Skills: Problem-Solving, Troubleshooting, Analytical Skills, Time Management, Creativity, Adaptability, and Initiative

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# SYLLABUS Inc. (STI College-Angeles)

Aug 2023 - June 2024

# IT Instructor

- Taught various IT courses including System Administration and Maintenance, Computer Programming, and Computer Graphics.
- Developed course materials and hands-on projects to enhance learning experiences.
- Guided students in the development of their Capstone projects, ensuring the quality and functionality of their applications.
- Acted as a panellist for IT students' thesis projects, providing critical feedback and recommendations.

# Fusion Manpower (Jollibee)

July 2019 - Sep 2019

#### **Service Crew**

- Provided excellent customer service, managed food preparation, and maintained store cleanliness.
- Demonstrated strong organizational and time management skills.

PC Bytes Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

#### IT Technician

- Built and troubleshoot client computers, installed operating systems, and applications.
- Provided technical support and maintenance for client systems.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science in Information Technology**

2019 - 2023

STI College-Angeles

College - Magna Cum Laude

• Specialized in web development, mobile app development, desktop app development. game development, networking & cloud computing, and Linux system administration.

# **Computer and Communication Technology**

2017 - 2019

STI College-Angeles

Senior High School - With Honors

• Specialized in Computer Hardware and Networking.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- Huawei Certified ICT Associate (HCIA) Cloud Computing Certification Huawei
- JAVA Explorer Oracle Academy
- Google Cybersecurity Professional Certificate Google

#### **PROJECTS**

- Kody's Adventure: Developed a 2D side-scrolling game in Unity to teach basic Python programming.
- Telegram Bots: Created a financial tracking chatbot using Python and SQLite.
- Online Guidance Counselling System: Contributed to a web project to digitalize guidance counselling tasks using MySQL, JQUERY, AJAX, PHP, and JavaScript.
- Trade Monitoring Mobile App: Developed an app to track trades and calculate risks using Java and SQLite.

# **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

- **Technical Assistance:** Provided support to family and neighbour with Wi-Fi and computer issues, including troubleshooting and configuring networks.
- LAN and Network Design: Crafted LAN cables, designed client networks, and configured fibre optic cables for network infrastructure.

#### **REFERENCES**

Louie A. Ruiz, MIT, MTA

Academic Head / STI College Angeles louie.ruiz@angeles.sti.edu.ph